Edward J. Mowery Papers
Edward J. Mowery Papers
1943-1970
Mowery, Edward J.
2.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American journalist, awarded Pulitzer Prize in 1953. Collection includes articles, clippings, newspaper columns, press releases, research materials, and pamphlets.
149348
Biographical History
Edward J. Mowery (1906-1970) was an American journalist, awarded the Pulitzer Prize in 1953 "for his reporting of the facts which brought vindication and freedom to Louis Hoffner," falsely convicted of murder.
Edward J. Mowery was born in Lancaster, Ohio on March 8, 1906. He attended Ohio State University and Notre Dame between 1924 and 1929, During his journalism career he served as feature writer and editor for many newspapers, including the Columbus Citizen, the Lancaster Daily Eagle, the New York Post, the New York World-Telegram, and the New York Herald Tribune. Starting in 1966 Mowery wrote a syndicated column, "Inside View," for General Features Syndicate.
Mowery received many journalism awards including two NBC "Big Story" awards (1947, 1953) and the 1953 Pulitzer Prize for Journalism. He also wrote two books, HUAC and the FBI: Targets for Abolition and Taxpayer's Governor.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Edward J. Mowery Papers consist of news clippings, news releases, writings and printed matter from Mowery's career in journalism.
Arrangement of the Collection
Clippings are arranged chronologically. Other material is arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Mowery, Edward J.; Journalism.; Journalists -- United States.; Newspapers -- Sections, columns, etc.; Clippings (information artifacts); Pamphlets.; Press releases.; Research notes.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- News clippings
  - 1943-1953, 1955-1969, 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Blue Cross series, 1959 (Box 1)
  - The Columbus Citizen, 1948-1951 (Box 1)
  - Congressional Record, 1965-1968 (Box 1)
  - Drugs, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Fidel Castro expose, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Irish series, 1964 (Box 1)
  - The New York Knickerbocker, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Old Brooklyn series, 1948 (Box 2)
- News releases
  - "Inside View" column, 1966-1968; 4 folders (Box 2)
- Writings
  - Books, pamphlets, articles, 1947-1950 (Box 2)
  - Research material
    - [Miscellaneous], 1964-1965 (Box 2)
    - Animals, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
    - Drugs, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Economy, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
    - Electric cars, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Stone Mountain memorial, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
    - Un-American Affairs Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
- Printed material
  - Pamphlets, articles, 1950-1970 (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets, Palestinian guerillas, 1964-1970 (Box 2)
  - Supplements to Cumulative Index to Publications of the Committee on Un-American Activities, 1955-1968 (Box 2)